##Announcements!

- **Please close the default WrapBootstrap iFrame when viewing from IE**
- Check out [SmartAdmin Bug Tracker](http://bootstraphunter.com/smartadmin/BUGTRACK/track_/ "Bug Tracker") for all reported issues and wish lists
- Version 1.4 now comes with Pure HTML Version, [Advanced PHP Version](http://myorange.ca/themes/preview/smartadmin/1.4/phpversion/ "PHP Version") with custom functions and [AngularJS Version](http://192.241.236.31/themes/preview/smartadmin/1.4/angularjs/ "AngularJS") (to help you get started)! 

If you have already purchased SmartAdmin you can redownload all future updates, at no extra cost, by visiting this link: https://wrapbootstrap.com/support/download-resender

#SmartAdmin - Responsive WebApp

**SmartAdmin WebApp** - goes beyond the ordinary admin template. Its unique flat design and responsive layout is crafted one of a kind. SmartAdmin comes with 4 different versions: Pure HTML, AJAX Version, PHP, and AngularJS version. SmartAdmin also adds flavor to 40+ customized jquery plugins including **5 unique plugins** (*exclusively catered for SmartAdmin*). SmartAdmin Layout API lets you customize your project for almost any device - be it Mobile, Web or WebApp - SmartAdmin has you covered! 

![SmartAdmin Responsive WebApp](http://192.241.236.31/smartadmin/publishing-images/multiple-layout-compressed-new)

##What our customers are saying...
![SmartAdmin Quotes](http://bootstraphunter.com/smartadmin/quotes.gif)

##Features include:

- **Carefully** hand coded from head to toe
- Contains **neatly organized** and commended HTML, JS and LESS files (unminified CSS files available)
- Built with **bootstrap 3.2** (contains LESS files for the Custom BS Build)
- **Retina** Graphs and Icons
- w3 valid cross browser compatible HTML5 markup
- Unique, never seen before, **localStorage Widgets** (*Jarvis Widget 2.0*) with custom controls for the users (now includes a robust API)
- **6 Level responsive navigation**
- Scales to almost **any size** (Fluid/Responsive/Boxed and Container)
- Two different navigation options (horizontal or vertical - no DOM changes required to switch between the two)
- CSS3 **Animated**
- **Modern** Form Elements (jQuery select2, colorpicker, datepicker, validation, iDevice buttons and wizard)
- **Professional Design** and **Branding** (includes matching email templates [non-Bootstrap])
- Unique menu API that can be collapsed, or hidden (show on hover). Menu also adapts on mobile phones very swiftly.
- Unique **Google Map Skins** (7 in total)
- Google like Gallery with **data-attribute descriptions**
- **Smart Alert** and **Smart Notification** with sound
- Dynamic Data Table with **export to PDF/Excel**
- **Smart Form elements** (built on top of bootstrap library for robust form development)
- **AJAX pages** (pages are pulled in and scripts are loaded on request per page)
- Also contains a Clean HTML Version, [Advanced PHP Version](http://myorange.ca/themes/preview/smartadmin/1.4/phpversion/ "PHP Version"), and [AngularJS Version](http://192.241.236.31/themes/preview/smartadmin/1.4/angularjs/ "AngularJS") with Grunt Tasks

###Change colors using LESS / SASS variables or use included themes
![SmartAdmin Responsive WebApp](http://192.241.236.31/smartadmin/publishing-images/smcolors-compressed.png)

##Supported resolutions

![SmartAdmin Responsive WebApp](http://www.myorange.ca/theme/jarvisadmin/publish-images/table.png)

##Special Features:

- Functional Inbox page (all you will need to do is code the backend)
- Sparkline, Easy Pie Charts and various *important* form elements are controlled by data-*attributes 
- Fully functional Calendar with Add event with color, description and icon
- Lighter pages (page scripts/plugins are loaded with a lazy load technique via ajax)
- Breadcrumbs are built automatically
- Various button types and colors
- Custom tree view
- Jquery UI Compatible

###Layout API

- Collapse Navigation (show on hover)
- Fixed header, ribbon and navigation
- Minified navigation - minifies the navigation to show only icons, reveals children on parent hover.
- metro type shortcut dropdown (click the username to show)


###Will be included in the future:

- More color options / themes - ***Now Available***
- Profile Page ***Now Available***
- Media CSS files for printing - ***Now Available***
- Forum Layout ***Now Available***
- Editable Tables ***Now Available***
- Pure HTML page without ajax - ***Now Available***
- Detailed Documentation ***Now Available***
- Modular LESS Files - ***Now Available***
- And many more features to discover

***Be smart in 2014 and go with SmartAdmin. It's Okay to be Smart!***

### Patch 1.4.1 (27/06/2014) - see docs for upgrade instructions

- Update plugins: pace.js, select2, bootstrap, progressbar, summernote
- Added SASS Files (in addition to LESS files)
- Responsive Datatables
- Google Voice Command implementation
- JS: Fixed memory leaks for a number of DOM elements
- JS: Added a new file app.config.js (all app configurations has been moved here for easy access)
- JS: Restructured app.js for HTML/AJAX/PHP
​- CSS: Fixed minor CSS bugs 
- Updated bootstrap core to latest version (3.2)

###Update 1.4 (05/06/2014) - see docs for upgrade instructions

- Fixed loading cog for AJAX pages
- Fixed all IE11 related bugs and compaibility issues 
- Removed ID #project-context and replaced with class .project-context 
- Fixed vertical scrolling issue for fixed left navigation 
- The function "nav_page_height()" has been made redundant
- Fixed the double scroll bar bug for bootstrap modals 
- Fixed CSS issue with bg-color pseudo classes that was conflicting with tabs 
- Resolved compatibility issue with HighCharts 
- Fixed Fullscreen function for HTML Version
- Fixed .NET MVC bug for form inputs 
- Fixed IE11 glitch for checkURL in app.js (AJAX Version)
- Scrollbar overlay in IE10 - this was happening due to bootstrap's @-ms-viewport { width: device-width; } which was initially intended for Windows 8 Metro. CSS has now been adjusted. IMPORTANT: Please note we have disabled this fix by default, to enable please edit "ie-fix.less" and recompile your CSS.
- For AJAX version on mobile view, selecting the items from the top #shortcut does not auto hide the menu Solution: we have now added data-attributes which you can use to close the navigation 
- Dygraphs integration 
- jQgrid Integration
- Upgrade to FontAwesome Library 4.1 
- Upgrade Datatable plugin to v1.10 
- Add Google Map custom pins with dynamic XML data (see google maps page and pins.xml) 
- Add flags page (showing all the flags of the world with a easy copy and paste reusable code) 
- Expand/Collapse table row
- Added functional data-attributes for Collapse Menu, Reset Widgets, User Logout, Toggle Shortcut, Minify Menu, and Full Screen - Functions 
- Localize files and assets with Grunt (Tasks include: minify CSS & JS files, compile LESS, concatinate JS files - more tasks can be added as required)  Note: We do not provide any tutorial to setup grunt as there are many videos and tutorials readily available on the internet
- Bootstrap modal content is now loaded dynamically for the AJAX version
- Added page footer (options: fixed, static, disable footer)
- Reduced page rendering time for mobile view by removing layout related javascripts and re-adjusting the CSS
- Added PHP Version of SmartAdmin
- Added Horizontal Navigation Option
- Add AngularJS Version of SmartAdmin
- Updated and organized LESS files and its structure

###Update 1.3 (28/02/2014)

- Upgrade to Bootstrap Framework 3.1.1
- Added Documentation
- Added 1 additional skin
- Added pages: Profile page, Forum page, Timeline page, Forgot password page
- Added Fullscreen function (does not support IE9)
- Updated app.js to have url with query strings like the google search - available only for the ajax version
- Added Splash screens and home screen icons for iDevices
- Slight DOM change was made to <div class="login-info">...</div>. CSS/LESS and CSS skins was updated accordingly. This was done to truncate long user names
- Added additional Bootstrap form elements (see the new section "Flexible Input fields with icons" inside the Bootstrap Form Elements page)
- Added logout message localization handler using data-attribute
- Define file path variable for sound files
- Fixed various CSS bugs and memory leaks
- Added PHP Version (beta release)

Read all changes here: http://bootstraphunter.com/smartadmin/BUGTRACK/track_/

###Update 1.2 (13/1/2014)

- Added non-ajax version for SmartAdmin
- Updated jarvis.widget to work with non-ajax page view (Jarvis widget now includes onSave and OnLoad hooks to be saved into the database) 
- app.js has been significantly reworked - users can switch on / off plugins and features more easily
- LESS files are now more modular, new variables are added for better control
- Update Select2 to latest version (3.4.5)
- All ajaxed pages now scroll to top when loading a new page
- Nav menu clicks now updates title
- Added new custom plugin "SmartClick" - this will counter the 300ms delay click in iDevices (this is turned off by default - see app.js to turn it on)
- Fixed CSS issue with X-editable date popup
- Fixed Android mobile menu bug
- Typo in main.less file that resulted certain @media width content to not adjust properly on iPad view
- Function for drawing breadcrumb was running for all ajax calls - this now checks the container and runs the function when appropriate
- Removed CSS3 wobble animation from menu items to save memory on touch devices
- Removed animation from menu slide in / out to save mobile memory
- Added the 3 missing images to the image library (also deleted reference to images in CSS that were not being used) 

###Update 1.1 (1/1/2014)

- SmartAdmin theme is now *built with LESS* - previous CSS files are deprecated!
- *Added 2 new Skins* - Dark Elegance and Ultra White (see the settings panel - cog icon top right corner )
- Improved repainting for touch devices 
- Fixed ajax bug and all IE 9 related issues (IE users will need to close the WrapBootstrap iFrame when viewing the demo)
- Ajax scripts now load faster

###Update 1.0

- Initial release